# Mayank Arora

### Senior Site Reliability Engineer

Spent 5 years developing the skills to increase reliability and quality for on-premise and cloud-based architecture(AWS) applications with a high focus on security. Experienced in the implementation and automation of monitoring stack along with automation via Ansible and Terraform.



mayankasitis@gmail.com



+91 9920070716



18/102 Fortune CHS, Powai Vihar, Powai, Mumbai -400076., Mumbai, India

#### in

linkedin.com/in/mayankaroraa

#### **SKILLS**

Site Reliability

Linux

**Ansible** 

**AWS** 

Docker

AppDynamics

Terraform

Python

Puppet

Splunk

Nagios

Nagios Xi

Apache Web Server

Nginx

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Senior Associate: Site Reliability Engineer Institutional Shareholder Services

11/2017 – 03/2020 Achievements/Tasks Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

- Implementation and Automation of Monitoring Stack and Level 3 Application Level Support for middleware and web layer.
- Capacity Management and ansible dynamic inventory management by fetching the server performance metrics via ansible crawler or PuppetDB.
- Creation of a self-sustained monitoring model with auto-discovery and automated configuration for Splunk, Nagios, and Appdynamics on different layers.
- Implementing correlation analysis/trend dashboarding with the scope of improving by application tuning and proactive monitoring.
- Ansible based automation for environment start/stop with dependencies and successful startup checks.
- Implementation of SLOs, SLAs and error budget policies.
- Actively worked in an agile software development environment to automate standard operating procedures around common failure scenarios.
- Implemented a continuous development pipeline via ansible.
- Consult and contribute to system architecture.

## Site Reliability Engineer ZYCUS INFOTECH

06/2015 – 11/2017 Achievements/Tasks

SEEPZE -MUMBAI

- Administering, Monitoring and troubleshooting the issues in the Products for Global Clients by configuring tools and understanding the full application flow.
- Performance Tuning of Applications and making the architecture robust and highly available. Techniques include Thread Analysis, JVM Tuning, JMX, and JDBC Tuning, Apache Tuning, Solving Slowness Issues.
- Working on POCs for Automations to reduce Process Time Cycles, Monitoring Tools, Health Dashboards, and Reactive to Proactive conversion of Monitors.
- Event management for monitoring alerts via tools like Pager-duty. Streamlining and automating the alerting mechanism with proper assigning to concerned teams.
- Managing Incident lifecycle and Bug management via Remedy tool.
- Implementation of AppDynamics on 1000+ nodes that include Controller, java agents, EVM, Machine agents, database agents, and synthetic monitoring.

## **Application Engineer**

### Wirecard acceptance technologies gmbh

05/2020 - Present

(Working remotely from Mumbai owing to covid pandemic)

Achievements/Tasks

- Production support for cloud based and on-prem systems.
- Implementation of monitoring via cloudwatch agents on Ec2 instances.
- Creation of ansible scripts for synchronous start/stop applications in a distributed environment with dependencies checks in place.
- Creating launch templates and using prebaked AMI's along with bootstrap for implementation of auto-scaling of Ec2 instances with ELB in place.

Muncih, Germany

#### **SKILLS**

Tomcat Application Container

#### **LANGUAGES**

**ENGLISH** 

**Full Professional Proficiency** 

HINDI

**Full Professional Proficiency** 

#### **HOBBIES**

wildlife and nature photography

#### **EDUCATION**

## Bachelor of Engineering, COMPUTER ENGINEERING K.C.COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING.

2011 – 2015 Mumbai, Maharastra

#### 12TH K.V.IIT POWAI

2010 - 2011

Mumbai, Maharastra

#### 10TH K.V.IIT POWAI

2008 - 2009

Mumbai, Maharastra

#### **DETAILED SKILLSET**

Ansible: Expertise in automating manual tasks and environment orchestration.

#### AWS:

VPC, EC2, Autoscaling, ELB, EBS, Security, RDS, S3, Route53, CloudWatch, CloudTrail, IAM

Terraform: Basic experience in automation and management of docker containers and AWS components

Extensive implementation and technical knowledge of

- Web Servers: Apache, Nginx.
- Application Servers: Apache Tomcat.

#### Linux

- Comfortable with Bash Scripting required for Monitoring, Automation or Debugging.
- Expertise in commands to debug issues on linux os, web tier and app tier in a distributed environment.

#### **AppDynamics**

- Controller and environment upgrades via Enterprise Console.
- Automated deployment of Java, Machine, and Database agents.
- Correlation analysis/trend dash-boarding of transaction performance and monitoring metrics

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Google SRE Certified from Coursera.

ITIL Level 1.

Certificate from Zycus infotech for Automating and Managing Appdynamics.